A Guide to the Weaver Orphan Home (Hampton, Va. ) Records, 1847-1978
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Weaver Orphan Home Records, 1901-1978., Extent: 42 boxes and 13 volumes. (Box 1-40, 54-55)
  - Resident Files
    - Whitehead, Walter. (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Williams, Irving Nathaniel. (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Williams, Oliver and Adam. (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Wright, Bryant. (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Yancey, Eunice. (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Yarborough, Levi and Alma. (Box 40, Folder 16)
- Series II. Gloucester Agricultural and Industrial School Records, 1877-1903., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 41-42)
  There is a small group of records of the Gloucester Agricultural and Industrial School that was co-founded by Weaver in 1888. Included are articles on the school, catalogues, circulars and forms, correspondence, deeds, programs, and teacher licenses. Of note is a minute and record book containing minutes from the school's formation, as well as invitations and flyers, including to programs where Frederick Douglass was the speaker. There is also a set of the school's monthly newsletter entitled The Gloucester Messenger, and The Gloucester Letter, which was written for a short time by Weaver after he severed his ties with the school.
  - Accounts and Receipts. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Address to Teachers, 1898. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - American Missionary Association Manual. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Appeal to American Missionary Association, 1890. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Article - Advancements of Education for Colored People. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Article - The Richmond Whig, 1883. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Article - Southern Workman, May 1893. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Bethel School. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Broadsides. (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Bylaws. (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Calendars. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Cash Accounts, 1894-1896. (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Catalogues. (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Charter. (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Circulars/Forms. (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Clippings. (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence. (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Deeds. (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Educational Conference and Tenth Anniversary Exercises, 1898. (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Examination of Teachers, 1877. (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - The Gloucester Letter, 1888-1900. (Box 42, Folder 1-13)
  - The Gloucester Messenger, 1899-1900. (Box 42, Folder 14-15)
  - Invitations. (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Letter to Board of Trustees, 9 October 1890. (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Letters of Introduction/Support (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Minutes (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - The News (Hampton, VA), 16 July 1881. (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Photograph - Weaver Residence, Cappahosic, VA (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Plat, 1885 (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Programs (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - "A Rural School Builder" by Lizzie Baytop Baker, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Sale of Cappahosic Land, 1903 (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - School Exercises (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Scrapbook of Estelle I. Sprague (Frederick Douglass Clippings), 1896. (Volume 10)
  - The Sunday School Missionary, April 1884. (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Taxes. (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Teacher's Licenses. (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - The Tract Repository. (Box 42, Folder 30)
- Series III. Weaver-Bolden-Fagan Family Papers, 1847-1978., Extent: 11 boxes. (Box 43-53)
  The Weaver-Bolden-Fagan family papers include calendars, condolences sent upon the death of Rev. Weaver, correspondence, deeds, diaries, ephemera, Hampton Institute Alumni Association materials, newsletters, newspapers, and programs. The diaries cover the period when Weaver left Gloucester County and moved to Hampton and founded the orphan home. Topics of the correspondence include courtship and wedding plans, and letters from Archer W. Bolden, Jr. (1860-1938) while he was stationed in the western United States with the 10th U.S. Cavalry and later with the 2nd New York Volunteer Infantry enroute to Cuba and Puerto Rico. There are also letters written by Ruth Weaver to her parents while she was attending Hampton Institute, and from Anna Fagan (1932-2002) to her parents while she was enrolled at Adrian College in Michigan.
  - Account Book, 1901. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and Receipts. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Address Books. (Box 43, Folder 3-4)
  - Albany High School. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Albany High School Merit Rolls, 1876-1879. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Almanacs. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Appointments, 1911, 1921. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Armstrong Technical High School. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Autograph Book, 1879-1882. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Birth Certificate - Rueben Price, 1922. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Bolden Family Bible Record. (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Books (Bibles, Classics, Educational, Hymns, Religious Tracts). (Box 51, Folder n/a)
  - Building Specifications. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Calendars. (Box 43, Folder 13-14)
  - Calling Cards. (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Car Accident, 1959. (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - The Christian Endeavor World, 29 September 1904. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Christian Herald and Signs of Our Times, 18 October 1888, 9, 23, and 30 January 1889, 19 July 1893, 9 September 1896. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Class Notes. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Class Notes - Chemistry. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Class Notes - Math. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Class Notes - Science. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - The Colored American (Washington, DC), 3 June 1893 and 21 January 1899. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Condolences, 1929. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Condolences - Lists and Flowers. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Condolences - Relatives. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Condolences - Telegrams. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1874. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1880-1899. (Box 44, Folder 9-28)
  - Correspondence, 1900-1966. (Box 45, Folder 1-37)
  - Correspondence, undated. (Box 45, Folder 38)
  - Daily Worker, 27 July 1935. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Deeds. (Box 45, Folder 39)
  - Diary, 1898. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1899. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1900. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Diary (Anna B. Weaver), 1901-1918. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1901-1902. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Diary (Anna B. Weaver), 1902. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1902-1904. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1905-1907. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1907-1908. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Diary, 1913-1915. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1917-1925. (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1924-1925. (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1926-1927. (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1931. (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1935-1939. (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Ephemera (Buttons, Ribbons, Fans, Printing Blocks, etc. (Box 52, Folder n/a)
  - The Examiner (New York), 23 December 1886. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - First Baptist Church (Hampton, VA). (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - First Baptist Church (Troy, NY). (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - The Freeman (Indianapolis IN), 20 September 1890. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Funeral of Ruth W. Fagan. (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Funeral of Spillman Fagan. (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Funeral of Cecelia Fagan McLeod. (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Funeral of Julia Weaver Nelson. (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Funeral of Anna B. Weaver. (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - The Gentlewoman's Record of the Glorious Reign of Victoria the Good, 23 September 1896. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - George Washington Bicentennial Commission Clip Sheet, 1931. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Greeting Cards. (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Hampton Hymnal and School Service, 1894. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Hampton Institute - Alumni Association, 1938-1953. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Hampton Institute - Alumni Association, 1957-1958. (Box 48, Folder 3-4)
  - Hampton Institute - Alumni Association, 1963. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Hampton Institute - Alumni Association, 1968-1969. (Box 48, Folder 6-11)
  - Hampton Institute - Alumni Association, 1970-1972, 1974. (Box 49, Folder 1-3)
  - Hampton Institute - Alumni Record. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Hampton Institute - Booklets/Brochures/Circulars. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Hampton Institute - Catalogue, 1872-1874. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Hampton Institute - The Hampton Bulletin. (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Hampton Institute - The Hampton Bulletin. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Hampton Institute - The Hampton Script. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Hampton Institute - The Hampton Student. (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Hampton Institute - Handbooks. (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Hampton Institute - Letter. (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Hampton Institute - Miscellaneous. (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Hampton Institute - Postcards/Photographs. (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Hampton Institute - Programs. (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Hampton Institute - Songs/Spirituals/Hymns. (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Hampton Institute - The Southern Workman. (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Hampton Institute - The Southern Workman. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - "Hampton Illustrated," 1892. (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Hartshorn Memorial College. (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - The Herald (Newport News VA),1 August 1920. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Hospital for Cripples, Epileptics, and Incurables, 1928. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Invitations. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Liberty Street Presbyterian Church (Troy, NY). (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - License to Preach Gospel, 1899. (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Lithograph - Lincoln Monument, Fairmount Park, Philadelphia. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Medical Records. (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum Books. (Box 50, Folder 6-8)
  - Military Records. (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Moore High Trumpet (Waco TX), December 1929, May 1930, February 1931. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - "Mrs. Weaver" by Marion L. Starkey, July 1938. (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - New York Evangelist, 27 October 1887, 12 July, 25 October, 15 November 1888, 1 and 22 August 1889. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - New York Central Railroad. (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - The The New York Freeman, 15 May 1886. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Oakwood Cemetery (Troy, NY). (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - On Habits and Manners by Mrs. M. F. Armstrong. (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Our Work at Home (Albany NY), February 1877. (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Pew Rents. (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Photograph - Gen. Samuel Armstrong Family. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Photograph - Unidentified - Small Girl with Doll. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Pledge. (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Postcards (Unused). (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Primary Picture Set - Course II, Part 2. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Product Catalogs. (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Program - Grand Union Services, 1863-1913. (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Rent Book (Hooper), 1857-1868. (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Richmond Planet, 8 September 1888 and 2 February 1889. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - The St. Joseph Daily Gazette (MO), 2 January 1881. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Savings Bank of the Grand Fountain, U.O.T.R. (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - The School Bulletin and New York State Educational Journal, March 1895. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - School Exercises. (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Sewage Disposal and Guano Company. (Box 50, Folder 24)
  - Resolution - Wesleyan Methodist Episcopal Zion Church (Troy NY), 1847. (Box 50, Folder 25)
  - Tax Receipts. (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Tidewater Liberal (Gloucester CH), 13 January 1883. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Tidewater Virginian (Gloucester CH), 16 September 1888 and 7 February 1889. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Troy Daily Times, 1894, 16 September 1896. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Troy High School. (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Troy Morning Telgram and Whig, 18 February 1881. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - The Troy Times, 5 and 12 April, 18 July 1914. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Union Gospel News (Cleveland OH), 26 February 1891. (Box 53, Folder n/a)
  - Washington, Booker T. (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - Weekly Unity, 1929. (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - Will of Delia Bolden. (Box 50, Folder 30)